const questions = [
    {
        question: "When was the first Super Mario Brothers game released?",
        optionA: "1983",
        optionB: "1985",
        optionC: "1988",
        optionD: "1980",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },
    {
        question: "How many games are in the original Megaman series?",
        optionA: "10",
        optionB: "12",
        optionC: "11",
        optionD: "9",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },
    {
        question: "Which games company is well known for creating the Dark Souls and Armoured Core series of games?",
        OptionA: "Konami",
        optionB: "Capcom",
        optionC: "Nintendo",
        optionD: "From Software",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },
    {
        question: "What was the name of Sega's first games console?",
        optionA: "The SG-1000",
        optionB: "The Master System",
        optionC: "The Megadrive",
        optionD: "The Sega Saturn",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },
    {
        question: "British games devs Rare had a hit on their hands with Goldeneye for the N64 but what year did they first begin to create games? ",
        optionA: "1980",
        optionB: "1984",
        optionC: "1985",
        optionD: "1982",
        correctOption: "optionC"
    },
    {
        question: "Nintendo broke into the market with the Famicom in 1983 but what was the name of the add on for that system?",
        optionA: "The Gameboy",
        optionB: "Disk System",
        optionC: "The Famicom Twin",
        optionD: "64DD",
        correctOption: "optionB"

    },
    {
        question: "The Castlevania series is one of Konami's best series of games but what is the name of the protagonist from the first title?",
        optionA: "Trevor Belmont",
        optionB: "Alucard",
        optionC: "Sypha Belnades",
        optionD: "Simon Belmont",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },
    {
        question: "Capcom are well known for their games such as Resident Evil and Street Fighter but what is Capcom and abbreviation of? ",
        optionA: "Capsule company ",
        optionB: "Capsule Computer",
        optionC: "Capsule Com",
        optionD: "Capsule Community",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },
    {
        question: "The Resident Evil series has had a few spin offs over the years but what is the title of the only Gameboy Colour game that was created in the series?",
        optionA: "Resident Evil 2",
        optionB: "Resident Evil Gaiden",
        optionC: "Resident Evil Deadly Silence",
        optionD: "Resident Evil Portable",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },
    {
        question: "Which manga artist has famously created art for the Dragon Quest series of games? ",
        optionA: "Akira Toriyama",
        optionB: "Katsuhiro Otomo",
        optionC: "Naoki Urasawa",
        optionD: "Rumiko Takahashi",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },

    {
        question: "In what game did Sonic the Hedgehog have his first debut?",
        optionA:"Sonic the Hedgehog",
        optionB:"Rad Racer",
        optionC:"Rad Mobile",
        optionD:"Fighting Vipers",
        correctOption:"optionC"
    },
    {
        question: "Nintendo were founded in 1889 in Kyoto, Japan what were they famous for making at the time?",
        optionA: "Pachislot",
        optionB: "Vending machines",
        optionC: "Alcohol",
        optionD: "Playing cards",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },
    {
        question: " In what year did Wario, Marios nemesis make his debut?",
        optionA:"1992",
        optionB:"1985",
        optionC:"1993",
        optionD:"1983",
        correctOption:"optionA"
    },
    {
        question: "Sega had a hit on it's hands with 'Nights into Dreams' for the Sega Saturn but who produced the game?",
        optionA: "Rieko Kodama",
        optionB: "Yu Suzuki",
        optionC: "Yuji Saito",
        optionD: "Yuji Naka",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },
    {
        question: "Final Fantasy 7(1997) featured a summon that took ages to finish their attack, what is their name?",
        optionA: "Neo Bahamut",
        optionB: "Odin",
        optionC: "Ifrit",
        optionD: "Knights of the round",
        correctOption: "optionD"
    },
    {
        question: "Pikmin was a hit on the Nintendo Gamecube but what type of game is it?",
        optionA: "Fishing simulator",
        optionB: "Real time strategy",
        optionC: "Platformer",
        optionD: "Beat 'em up",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },
    {
        question: " Every game in the Final Fantasy series contains a character with which name?",
        optionA: "Locke",
        optionB: "Cid",
        optionC: "Kefka",
        optionD: "Garland",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },
    {
        question: " Captain Falcon originally appeared in what game?",
        optionA:"Earthbound",
        optionB:"Pilot Wings",
        optionC:"F-Zero",
        optionD:"Star Fox",
        correctOption:"optionC"
    },
    {
        question: "Earthbound is a classic JRPG, what is the name of the series creator? ",
        optionA: "Shigeru Miyamoto",
        optionB: "Shigesato Itoi",
        optionC: "Hironobu Sakaguchi",
        optionD: "Yu Suzuki",
        correctOption: "optionB"
    },
    {
        question: "Donkey Kong JR is a spin off of the arcade classic which had it's own spin off which taught...?",
        optionA: "Maths",
        optionB: "English",
        optionC: "Science",
        optionD: "Philosophy",
        correctOption: "optionA"
    },
];

